[
    {
        "question": "Nobel prize is awarded for which of the following disciplines?",
        "options": [
            "Literature, peace and economics",
            "Medicine or Physiology",
            "Chemistry and Physics",
            "All the above"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Sun exposure can bring about an improvement in health because of which of the following reasons?",
        "options": [
            "the infrared light kills bacteria in the body",
            "resistance power increases",
            "the pigment cells in the skin get stimulated and produce a healthy tan",
            "the ultraviolet rays convert skin oil into Vitamin D"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
        {
        "question": "The Indian, who holds the pride of beating the computers in mathematical wizard is?",
        "options": [
            "Shakuntala Devi",
            "Raja Ramanna",
            "Ramanujam",
            "Rina Panigrahi"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is basically red?",
        "options": [
            "Oliver",
            "Ivory",
            "Maroon",
            "Aqua"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the strongest metal",
        "options": [
            "Tungsten",
            "Diamond",
            "Vibranium",
            "Adamantium"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The radioactive element radium was invented by which of the following scientists?",
        "options": [
            "Marie Curie",
            "Benjamin Franklin",
            "Albert Einstein",
            "Isaac Newton"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following items was introduced by James Watt?",
        "options": [
            "Hot air balloon",
            "Steam boat",
            "Diving bell",
            "Rotary Steam Engine"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the most preferable language when it comes to running time?",
        "options": [
            "Java",
            "Python",
            "c",
            "R"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Generic is most similar in meaning to",
        "options": [
            "Branded",
            "Basic",
            "Trademarked",
            "Altruist"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Ctrl, Shift and Alt are called _____ keys.",
        "options": [
            "modifier",
            "function",
            "alphanumeric",
            "adjustment"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The blue colour of the clear sky is due to",
        "options": [
            "Diffraction of light",
            "Dispersion of light",
            "Reflection of light",
            "Refraction of light"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used in pencils?",
        "options": [
            "Silicon",
            "Phosphorous",
            "Graphite",
            "Charcoal"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following parts of the sun is easily visible only during a total solar eclipse?",
        "options": [
            "core",
            "photosphere",
            "sunspots",
            "corona"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "When a gas is turned into a liquid, the process is called",
        "options": [
            "condensation",
            "evaporation",
            "deposition",
            "sublimation"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The Ozone Layer restricts from",
        "options": [
            "Infrared Rays",
            "Radio waves",
            "Ultraviolet Radiation",
            "X-Rays and Gamma Rays"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The filament of an electric bulb is made of?",
        "options": [
            "tungsten",
            "nichrome",
            "graphite",
            "iron"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mudumalai National Park is located in which state ?",
        "options": [
            "Chattisgarh",
            "Haryana",
            "Tamil Nadu",
            "Kerala"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "In a laser (say neon laser) all the atoms emit the light waves of",
        "options": [
            "Same frequency",
            "Same amplitude",
            "Same phase",
            "All the above"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Iodine test is used to detect",
        "options": [
            "Carbohydrate",
            "Fat",
            "Protein",
            "Cholesterol"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following metals forms an amalgam with other metals ?",
        "options": [
            "Zinc",
            "Mercury",
            "Tin",
            "Lead"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Seawater (i.e. saltwater) freezes at:(in deg C)",
        "options": [
            "Below 100",
            "At 100",
            "Above 100",
            "seawater does not freeze"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Of the following, which element is common to all acids",
        "options": [
            "carbon",
            "hydrogen",
            "sulphur",
            "oxygen"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Smallest of all the continents?",
        "options": [
            "Asia",
            "Australia",
            "Africa",
            "America"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the largest of all the Deserts?",
        "options": [
            "Thar",
            "Sahara",
            "Kalahari",
            "Arabian"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The famous Rock Garden is located in which city?",
        "options": [
            "Chandigar",
            "Jaipur",
            "Simla",
            "Lucknow"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The Petronas Twin Towers is located in which country?",
        "options": [
            "Malaysia",
            "Singapore",
            "Thailand",
            "Brazil"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    }
]